<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Cameron Stokes's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-10-09T21:20:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cameron Stokes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Pandora Bookmarklet]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/09/21/new-pandora-bookmarklet/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/09/21/new-pandora-bookmarklet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.pandora.com/pandora/archives/2011/09/new-pandora-for.html">New Pandora</a> has launched, so it&#8217;s time for a #NewPandora bookmarklet. Here you go&#8230;</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re using Firefox, <a href="javascript:function%20pandora(){window.open('http://pandora.com/','_blank','width=850,height=120,scrollbars=1,location=0,menubar=0,titlebar=0,toolbar=0');}pandora();">bookmark this link</a>.</p>

<p>If you&#8217;re using Chrome, click the <em>view source</em> icon in the prettified code below, then copy and paste it into a new bookmark:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='javascript'><span class='line'><span class="nx">javascript</span><span class="o">:</span> <span class="kd">function</span> <span class="nx">pandora</span><span class="p">()</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">window</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">open</span><span class="p">(</span> <span class="s1">&#39;http://pandora.com/&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>                 <span class="s1">&#39;_blank&#39;</span><span class="p">,</span>
</span><span class='line'>                 <span class="s1">&#39;width=850,height=120,&#39;</span> <span class="o">+</span>
</span><span class='line'>                 <span class="s1">&#39;scrollbars=0,location=0,menubar=0,titlebar=0,toolbar=0&#39;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="p">);</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="p">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nx">pandora</span><span class="p">();</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grails and 204 "No Content" responses]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/08/15/grails-and-204-no-content-responses/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/08/15/grails-and-204-no-content-responses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hacking away on a project recently I decided to use the lesser-known HTTP status code 204 <em>No Content</em>. A 204 <em>No Content</em> indicates a successful request, but also that there&#8217;s no content to return. I&#8217;m using 204&#8217;s for responding to AJAX calls to server-side resources for which no content is needed to return. Technically I could use a 200 status code but I want to be as semantically correct as possible.</p>

<p>Using <a href="http://grails.org/">Grails</a> for the project it was super simple to return 204 from my controller. Here&#8217;s how you do it:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>class ResourceController {
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def update = {
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    // service.update params
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    render status: 204
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  }
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>} </span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>That&#8217;s it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting: Trailhead ISA]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/08/04/tasting-trailhead-isa/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/08/04/tasting-trailhead-isa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Trailhead ISA</strong></em> from Two Beers Brewing Co. is dubbed an India Style Session Ale but classified an IPA. At 4.8% ABV it doesn’t fit into the strictest standards of a Session Ale but is close nonetheless. It is probably the lowest ABV IPA I’ve had, yet still supplies enough hop flavor and bitterness to be an American IPA rather than an English IPA.</p>

<p>Two Beers recently ventured into canning their beer and Trailhead ISA is one of three initial styles available in cans from them. Per their <a href="https://www.facebook.com/note.php?note_id=10150230586597558">press release</a>, Two Beers is the first Washington State craft brewery to introduce 12-ounce cans. Their wording begs the question: which Washington State craft brewery is canning but not in 12-ouncers?</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/two-beers-trailhead-isa-can.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Trailhead ISA" ></p>

<h2>Beer Facts</h2>

<p><strong>Name</strong>: Trailhead ISA</p>

<p><strong>Style</strong>: India Style Session Ale/American IPA</p>

<p><strong>Brewery</strong>: Two Beers Brewing Co.</p>

<p><strong>Released</strong>: Year round</p>

<p><strong>Availability</strong>: 12-ounce cans and draft</p>

<p><strong>Description:</strong></p>

<blockquote>Toss this beer in a backpack and hit the trail to find freedom, escape, and a more simple life. As the sky above and good friends keep you company this generously dry-hopped ISA will complete the trinity of the good life. Pack it in. Pack it out. Cheers!</blockquote>


<p><strong>Hops:</strong> ?</p>

<p><strong>Malts:</strong> ?</p>

<p><strong>OG:</strong> ?</p>

<p><strong>FG:</strong> ?</p>

<p><strong>IBUs:</strong> ?</p>

<p><strong>ABV:</strong> 4.8%</p>

<h2>Tasting</h2>

<p><strong>Serving</strong>: 12-ounce can into a pint glass.</p>

<p><strong>Appearance</strong>: Slight orange, straw color. Half-inch of frothy head. Lots of lacing leftover. Haze that to fade as it warms.</p>

<p><strong>Aroma</strong>: Lots of piney hop aroma. Sweet malt comes through as it warms.</p>

<p><strong>Mouthfeel</strong>: High carbonation, but not over-carbonated. Light mouthfeel.</p>

<p><strong>Taste</strong>: Very bitter upfront, but dissipates quickly. Grainy malt flavor behind the hops. Very little lingering flavor after each sip.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/08/two-beers-trailhead-isa-glass.jpg" width="321" height="480" title="Trailhead ISA" ></p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I really, really like this beer. While the rest of the beer world is crazy about IPAs I tend to steer clear of them, finding myself drawn to more subtle lagers or complex stouts, Belgians, or sours. Having said that, I think Trailhead ISA is going to become a mainstay in my fridge. It is true to its name, it is a session ale. It is certainly a weak IPA by most standards but is very, very drinkable. On top of that, it comes in cans and I’m a sucker for a good beer in a can. Did I mentioned it&#8217;s very drinkable? I think I&#8217;ll have another.</p>

<p><strong>Food pairings</strong>: BBQs, lighter fare.</p>

<p><strong>Cellar-able</strong>: Nope.</p>

<p><strong>Comparable beers</strong>: Johnny Utah Session IPA from Georgetown Brewing, IPA Junior from Red Rock. (Haven’t had either of these.)</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li>No brewery link.</li>
<li><a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/17005/69549">Beeradvocate</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratebeer.com/beer/two-beers-trailhead-isa/148823/">ratebeer</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Compressed Content, Amazon S3, and CloudFront]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/07/20/compressed-content-amazon-s3-and-cloudfront/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/07/20/compressed-content-amazon-s3-and-cloudfront</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently published a static website to <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3)</a> and started looking for ways to improve performance. There weren&#8217;t any inherent performance problems using S3 by itself but I wanted to squeeze out every bit of performance I could. I first looked at typical website performance techniques such as <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#minify">minifying files</a>, <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#css_top">putting stylesheets at the top</a>, and <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#js_bottom">scripts at the bottom</a>, but wanted to keep going. My next steps were to <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#gzip">GZIP components</a> and <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#cdn">use a content delivery network</a>. Fortunately Amazon makes both of these easy with S3 and <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/">Amazon CloudFront</a>.</p>

<p>Storing GZIP content on S3 takes a mere 3 steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>GZIP content</li>
<li>Upload to S3</li>
<li>Set metadata on content</li>
</ol>


<p>For my small site I ran GZIP on all of my files manually at the command-line, but this could be easily scripted. From the command-line it looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ gzip -c site/index.html &gt; compressed/index.html
</span><span class='line'>$ gzip -c site/_packed/application.js &gt; compressed/_packed/application.js
</span><span class='line'>$ gzip -c site/_packed/application.css &gt; compressed/_packed/application.css </span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>After uploading the files to S3 I needed to set their metadata to indicate they&#8217;re GZIP encoded. In the <em>S3</em> tab within the Amazon Management Console, this is done by selecting each object and going to the <em>Metadata</em> tab on an object&#8217;s properties and adding the <em>Content-Encoding</em> key and value shown here:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/metadata-gzip.png" width="466" height="204" title="metadata-gzip" ></p>

<p>At this point you can test your compressed content by opening one of your files in your browser and making sure it renders appropriately.</p>

<p>Distributing content on the Amazon CloudFront CDN takes even fewer steps:</p>

<ol>
<li>Setup CloudFront distribution</li>
<li>Setup DNS CNAME record (such as www.example.com)</li>
</ol>


<p>Back in the AWS Management Console, in the <em>CloundFront</em> tab, click <em>Create Distribution</em> and select your S3 bucket from above as your origin. Enter the <em>CNAME</em> you plan to use and your <em>Default Root Object</em> and click through the rest of the wizard. At this point Amazon distributes your configuration to its CloudFront network, which seems to take about 5-10 minutes on average. Meanwhile, Amazon will assign your CloudFront <em>Domain Name</em> which you should set  CNAME  to in your DNS provider. You&#8217;re done&#8230;</p>

<p>At this point  your website  content is compressed, stored in a bucket on S3 and distributed on CloudFront. If you use Amazon&#8217;s <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/route53/">Route53</a> DNS service, your entire site is running in the cloud.</p>

<p>Cursory tests show significant improvements across each level of changes:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/cloudfront-response-times.png" width="504" height="329" title="cloudfront-response-times" ></p>

<p>To summarize, hosting a static website on S3 and CloudFront from Amazon Web Services is not only easy but also can drastically improve performance of your site.</p>

<p><em>(If you use Amazon&#8217;s Route53 DNS service, I find <a href="http://www.interstate53.com/">www.interstate53.com</a> to be the best management interface out there currently.)</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting: Grand Teton Sheep Eater]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/07/16/tasting-grand-teton-sheep-eater/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/07/16/tasting-grand-teton-sheep-eater</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Sheep Eater Scotch Ale</strong></em> from Grand Teton Brewing Co. is a scotch ale from the brewery&#8217;s Cellar Reserve series. Per the brewery website, it is brewed &#8221; to showcase the role of malt in the flavor of beer&#8221; and is brewed in   adherence to the German Beer Purity Law <em>Reinheitsgebot</em>. Having never heard of the brewery, I was excited to try the beer.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/grand-teton-sheep-eater-bottle.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Sheep Eater Scotch Ale from Grand Teton brewing Co." ></p>

<h2>Beer Facts</h2>

<p><strong>Name</strong>: Sheep Eater Scotch Ale</p>

<p><strong>Style</strong>: Scotch Ale</p>

<p><strong>Brewery</strong>: Grand Teton brewing Co.</p>

<p><strong>Released</strong>: One-time in 2009</p>

<p><strong>Availability</strong>: 1-liter, flip-top bottles</p>

<p><strong>Description</strong>:</p>

<blockquote>Sheep Eater Scotch Ale was brewed to showcase the  role of malt in the flavor of beer and brewed in strict adherence to the  Reinheitsgebot, or German Beer Purity Law.

Scotch Ales are some of the world&#8217;s most  flavorful beers.  Scotland&#8217;s cold, blustery climate lends itself to the  growing of barley and oats, but not to the production of hops, which are  almost always added sparingly.

The yeast must work at cooler temperatures than  is customary for ales, resulting in maltier, cleaner, less fruity or  estery, beers. The color often comes from black roasted malt, which  imparts some dryness, but because of the lower attenuation and hopping  rates, Scottish ales are almost always slightly sweet and incredibly  drinkable.

Ours was brewed with black roasted barley,  biscuit and peat-smoked malt.  It was gently hopped, fermented cool and  aged cold for weeks for smoothness.  It is copper-brown in color, with  some sweet maltiness and plenty of body.

Try it with ham, roast pork or chicken, roasted  vegetables or venison, crème brulee or, most traditionally, Scottish  butter shortbread cookies.</blockquote>


<p><strong>Hops</strong>: ?</p>

<p><strong>Malts</strong>: Black roasted barley, biscuit malt, peat-smoked malt</p>

<p><strong>OG</strong>: ?</p>

<p><strong>FG</strong>: ?</p>

<p><strong>IBUs</strong>: ?</p>

<p><strong>ABV</strong>: 7.5%</p>

<h2>Tasting</h2>

<p><strong>Serving</strong>: From a 1-liter, flip-top bottle into a Dogfish Head Signature Glass.</p>

<p><strong>Appearance</strong>: Pours an opaque, copper brown. One finger of head off the first pour.</p>

<p><strong>Aroma</strong>: Sweet, roasty, and smokey malt. No discernible hops or alcohol aroma.</p>

<p><strong>Mouthfeel</strong>: Thick mouthfeel, but not syrupy. Medium to low amount of carbonation, the perfect amount.</p>

<p><strong>Taste</strong>: Sweet malts, but not cloying. Just the right amount of roasty, smokey malt flavor. Raisins and toffee after taste. Slight alcohol presence.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/grand-teton-sheep-eater-glass.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Sheep Eater Scotch Ale from Grand Teton brewing Co." ></p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>For a brewery I&#8217;ve never heard of in the middle of nowhere Idaho, I&#8217;m damn impressed. Every aspect of the beer was spot on: the mouthfeel, complexities of flavor, and even carbonation, surprising for a flip-top bottle.</p>

<p><strong>Food pairings</strong>: A hearty meal. Shepherd&#8217;s pie, meatloaf, etc.</p>

<p><strong>Cellar-able</strong>: I would say yes, but Grand Teton&#8217;s Cellar Master says to drink it now. (<a href="http://grandtetoncellar.blogspot.com/2011/01/sheep-eater-at-one-year.html">Link</a>)<strong> </strong></p>

<p><strong>Comparable beers</strong>: Founders Dirty Bastard.</p>

<p>The night we tried Sheep Eater Scotch Ale we paired it with homemade shepherd&#8217;s pie. It was a perfect combination.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/grand-teton-sheep-eater-dinner.jpg" width="480" height="465" title="Sheep Eater and Shepherd's Pie" ></p>

<p>Coincidentally, on our <a href="../2011/04/24/something-new-atlanta-to-seattle/">drive from Atlanta to Seattle in April</a> we drove right by  Grand Teton Brewing Co. in  Victor, ID. Had known this beforehand I would have made sure they were open they were open.  I&#8217;m now on the lookout for other Grand Teton beers to try, but unfortunately was told by local beer store that they no longer distribute to Washington. Hopefully this isn&#8217;t true.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/grand-teton-brew-pub.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Grand Teton Brewing Co. in Victor, ID" ></p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.grandtetonbrewing.com/SESA.html">Brewery Link</a></li>
<li><a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/413/55370">BeerAdvocate</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratebeer.com/beer/grand-teton-sheep-eater-scotch-ale/116073/">ratebeer</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Twitter Widget for Wordpress]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/06/24/fast-twitter-widget-for-wordpress/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/06/24/fast-twitter-widget-for-wordpress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>tl;dr version&#8230;</strong> for loading your Twitter stream on your Wordpress blog, <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/reliable-twitter/">Reliable Twitter</a></em><em> is a fast and </em><em>reliable way to do it without impacting performance and usability of your blog.</em></p>

<p>I noticed my blog  performing slowly recently and, knowing that <a href="http://www.useit.com/alertbox/response-times.html">performance impacts site engagement</a>, I set out to fix it.</p>

<p>In particular, the main column loaded quickly but my Twitter stream in the right column would hang.  A quick look showed that the Twitter widget I was using, <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/twitter-widget-pro/">Twitter Widget Pro</a>, was loading the stream on the server and that response times from Twitter were likely the culprit. I began looking for an AJAX-based widget knowing that loading the data asynchronously could help initial page load time without impacting usability of my blog. After too much searching, I found an AJAX-based widget, coincidentally called <a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/reliable-twitter/">Reliable Twitter</a>, that fit the bill. After installing Reliable Twitter, I immediately noticed page loads were quicker and after a bit of time <a href="http://pingdom.com/">Pingdom</a> confirmed this.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/pingdom-cameronstokes-com.png" width="563" height="206" title="pingdom-cameronstokes-com" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Conflicting getter definitions with Groovy and Jackson]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/06/19/conflicting-getter-definitions-with-groovy-and-jackson/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/06/19/conflicting-getter-definitions-with-groovy-and-jackson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been piecing together <em><a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/">Groovy</a></em> and <a href="http://jackson.codehaus.org/"><em>Jackson JSON Processor</em></a> for a recent project (both making the project a breeze to get up and running) and quickly ran into an exception that at first glance may be a bit confusing but the fix was quite simple. The exception was:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'> java.lang.IllegalArgumentException: Conflicting getter definitions for property "error": pix.Response#isError(0 params) vs pix.Response#getError(0 params)
</span><span class='line'>  at ... </span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The reason for the exception is that Groovy automatically generates <em>isProperty()</em> and <em>getProperty()</em> methods for <em>boolean</em> properties on beans. Groovy is a little too clever in this case and Jackson gives up when it sees both.</p>

<p>Assuming a simple Groovy bean:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'> <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">GroovyBean</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">boolean</span> <span class="n">error</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kc">false</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">String</span> <span class="n">name</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The Groovy compiler really turns this into:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'> <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">GroovyBean</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">boolean</span> <span class="n">error</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kc">false</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">String</span> <span class="n">name</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">def</span> <span class="nf">getError</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">error</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">def</span> <span class="nf">isError</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">error</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">...</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>The fix is to explicitly define a <em>getError()</em> method in our <em>GroovyBean</em> class. This way the Groovy compiler won&#8217;t automatically generate both getters. (Unfortunately, the Groovy compiler still generates <em>getError() </em>if you define <em>isError()</em> so we&#8217;re stuck with <em>getError().)</em> Our new GroovyBean would look like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'> <span class="kd">public</span> <span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">GroovyBean</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">boolean</span> <span class="n">error</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="kc">false</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">String</span> <span class="n">name</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">def</span> <span class="nf">getError</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">error</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">...</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><em></em> After this change our GroovyBean is serialized into this:</p>

<pre>{"name":"","error":true}</pre>


<p>I like simple fixes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The past 3 months]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/30/past-3-months/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/30/past-3-months</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past 3 months I have&#8230;</p>

<ul>
    <li>Flown over 45,000 miles through 10 airports</li>
    <li>Driven over 1,000 miles across Europe</li>
    <li>Driven over 3,000 miles across the U.S.</li>
    <li>Driven through 11 states</li>
    <li>Visited 10 countries across 3 continents</li>
    <li>Spent over 40 nights in hotels</li>
    <li><a href="http://cameronstokes.com/2011/04/24/something-new-atlanta-to-seattle/">Moved from Atlanta to Seattle</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I am now settled into a new home and despite the stress of the extra travel and cross-country move, it&#8217;s all been worth it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update: Replacement UPS batteries and RefurbUPS.com]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/14/update-replacement-ups-batteries-and-refurbups-com/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/14/update-replacement-ups-batteries-and-refurbups-com</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quick and disappointing update to my <a href="http://cameronstokes.com/2010/08/23/replacement-ups-batteries-refurbups-com/"><em>Replacement UPS batteries and RefurbUPS.com</em></a> post from last year. Unfortunately, one of the replacement UPS batteries from RefurbUPS has already died and the second one seems to be on the fritz as well. I contacted RefurbUPS through their website and haven&#8217;t heard back. That was 3 months ago. Once this one finally goes kaput I&#8217;ll be replacing it with an OEM battery.</p>

<p>I no longer recommend RefurbUPS.com.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/11/atlanta-to-seattle-day-6/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/11/atlanta-to-seattle-day-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that   she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We  opted  to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of  posts  will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 6</h1>

<p>Day 6 was our last and final day of driving cross-country from Atlanta to Seattle. It was our longest day of driving of the entire trip (well the longest <em>planned</em> day). We were leaving Twin Falls, ID for Seattle, over 600 miles and supposed to take over 10 hours.</p>

<p>We left the hotel around 8:30 AM, gassed up the truck, and hit the road. Rhonda had looked up the story behind Twin Falls before we left and read that the falls were actually worth seeing. I made a deal with her that if they were within 5 miles of our hotel we would take the detour to go see them. It turns out Shoshone Falls was only 4.7 miles away. It turns out Shoshone Falls is actually taller than Niagara Falls, interesting because Rhonda and I had visited Niagara about 6 months earlier.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/shoshone-falls.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Rhonda in front of Shoshone Falls" ></p>

<p>After Shoshone Falls we made our away across the Perinne Bridge across the Snake River Canyon and were surprised to see someone jump off the bridge!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/parachuting.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Parachuting from the Perrine Bridge" ></p>

<p>I read after the fact that just down from this bridge, Evel Knievel unsuccessfully tried to jump the Snake River Canyon on a motorcycle (see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evel_Knievel#Snake_River_Canyon">Wikipedia</a>).</p>

<p>After the excitement of the falls and the BASE jumpers, the rest of the drive was pretty boring. The next notable bit of scenery came as we passed into Washington and saw hops fields on our way into Yakima Valley.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/hops-fields.jpg" width="480" height="300" title="Hops Fields in Washington" ></p>

<p>As we finished the drive into Seattle our excitement began to build as we thought of the coming weeks and months as we settled into our new home. Washington seemed to be the most beautiful stretch of the drive since we left Atlanta, undoubtedly influenced by our excitement. As we arrived in Seattle, the sun was shining and there was barely a cloud in the sky. We took it as a sign of things to come.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/seattle.jpg" width="480" height="360" title="Seattle" ></p>

<p>Total driving on our last day was over 600 miles and right around 10 hours.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/09/atlanta-to-seattle-day-5/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/09/atlanta-to-seattle-day-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that  she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted  to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts  will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 5</h1>

<p>The next morning I set out early to check the roads for our escape  from Tetonia. The night before at least 6 inches of snow had come down. I  swept off as much snow as I could from the truck and hit the road. As I  turned down Highway 32 for the second time I noticed the sign we had  missed the night before, &#8220;TRAVEL AT YOUR OWN RISK&#8221;. A plow had gone through before I got there and I drove a decent ways down to get a feel for  the drive. Once comfortable I texted Rhonda and told her we were  hitting the road.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/travel-at-own-risk.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Travel at Your Own Risk" ></p>

<p>Once I picked up Rhonda and the dogs we made our third attempt for Yellowstone. Turning onto Highway 32 again we reminisced about the night before and how much better the roads were. Unfortunately the road had only been cleared a few miles down the road and we hit packed snow and ice again. Not knowing how far the roads would be bad we kept going. A few miles later we passed a plow going the opposite way and the roads were fine the rest of the way to Yellowstone.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/snow-plow.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="A Snow Plow When We Needed Him" ></p>

<p>We passed through the entrance to Yellowstone around 10:30 AM and made our way toward Old Faithful. On the road to Old Faithful, we saw many Elk and Bison along the side of the road and in the middle of the road in the case of some Bison. Our dogs, Blue and Violet, pitched a fit with every animal we passed. The Bison were easily the largest animals Blue and Violet had ever seen, I only wish I knew what they were thinking. In some cases the Bison were only a few feet from our car.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/bison.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Bison on the Road" ></p>

<p>Old Faithful was about 30 minutes away from erupting when we arrived. We walked the dogs around and tried to stay warm. We were one of 5 people when we first got there and by the time Old Faithful was about to erupt there was a crowd of about 30. I think we were the only 30 people in the park that day. Old Faithful erupted and captured everyone&#8217;s attention for about 90 seconds, Blue and Violet&#8217;s included. I had visited Old Faithful once before when I was about 10 years old but couldn&#8217;t remember how amazing it really was. Water erupting from a hole in the earth is a truly magical site and one that occurs seemingly like clockwork is even more amazing.</p>

<p>After Old Faithful we walked around the geothermal pools for a while and decided to head for the Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone. We passed many more Bison and even sat in park on the road for about 10 minutes waiting for some to clear from the road. I would have been happy to sit there and watch them except that an RV drove up from the other way and waived a plastic bag out the window and scared them off the road. We found the Grand Canyon of the Yellowstone, snapped some photos, and made our way for the exit. Being the first week the park was open to visitors, most of the park was actually still closed, so we saw as much as we could.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/grand-canyon-of-yellowstone.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Grand Canyon of The Yellowstone" ></p>

<p>Yellowstone gave us one last surprise on our way out&#8230; a gray wolf!</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/gray-wolf.jpg" width="480" height="300" title="A Gray Wolf in Yellowstone" ></p>

<p>That night we had reservations in Twin Falls, ID about 4 and a half hours away. We made it in roughly that time on smooth, dry, non-icy roads. It was a welcome change from the night before. We arrived at our La Quinta in Twin Falls and I went out to pick up some dinner. We ate dinner, had a beer or 2, and turned in for the night.</p>

<p>Total driving on day 5 was about 300 miles through Wyoming, Montana, and Idaho.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/02/atlanta-to-seattle-day-4/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/05/02/atlanta-to-seattle-day-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 4</h1>

<p>Day 4 we left Fort Collins, CO with our eyes set for West Yellowstone, MO driving through <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jackson,_Wyoming">Jackson, WY</a>. The day started out as any other day, little did we know what we were in for&#8230;</p>

<p>The drive to Jackson was uneventful as were the previous 3 days except by the time we arrived in Jackson we realized we had made a crucial error in underestimating the drive. Somehow in the confusion of mapping the drive, booking hotels, planning the move, and so on what we thought was a 7 hour drive to West Yellowstone was really a 7 hour drive to Jackson and West Yellowstone was another 3 hours down the road.</p>

<p>Not having done our research on the weather or Yellowstone, we trekked on to the South entrance of the park through <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grand_Teton_National_Park">Grand Teton National Park</a>. We soon learned of our second crucial mistake for the day, though the severity of it would become apparent later. It turns out the South entrance to Yellowstone was not yet open for the season. The snow on the ground should have been our fist clue&#8230; Our only option was to go back through Jackson and around the park. We saw as much of Grand Teton National Park as we could (see exhibit a below) and made our way back to Jackson. Almost as soon as we had turned around I spotted two moose (meese?) off the road. We pulled over and snapped a few hundred photos of them. Once we had drawn a crowd of other cars and once the dogs had taken notice of the moose and started to pitch a fit we kept on moving. (As Rhonda would learn the next day in Yellowstone, if you see a car on the side of the road, there&#8217;s wildlife nearby.)</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/moose.jpg" width="480" height="329" title="Moose in Grand Teton National Park" ></p>

<p>Back in Jackson we turned onto Highway 22 for West Yellowstone. As with the snow, the &#8220;RETURN TO JACKSON WHEN FLASHING&#8221; sign should have been a warning of our impending doom. Nevertheless we kept going and soon found our way going through what I now affectionately call Dead Man&#8217;s Pass. Dead Man&#8217;s Pass is the stretch of Highway 22 that passes through the Grand Tetons from Jackson  to Idaho. As we climbed the Tetons it began to snow. As it snowed the road became icy. Soon enough we were going about 15 MPH on packed ice and snow. Unfortunately the cars ahead of me decided to slow to a crawl and then to a stop and my truck was unable to get traction again and we were stuck. The late 80&#8217;s Ford Taurus behind me (one straight out of Christmas Vacation) was stuck as well and the cars behind him just began to pass us. After several futile attempts at getting moving again we slid and backed up enough to get going back down the mountain. Once I found a suitable place to pull over we stopped and collected our thoughts. The Taurus had already turned around for another try. Despite the conditions I convinced Rhonda to let me try one more attempt before giving up and staying in Jackson for the night.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/highway-22-tetons.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Highway 22 through The Tetons" ></p>

<p>This time I was able to make it all the way up the mountain and down the other side. Had we had to have stopped as before we would have undoubtedly been stuck again but luckily we did not. Our friend in the Taurus was not so lucky as we passed him as he was heading back down the mountain as before. On the Idaho side of the Tetons the roads cleared up again and I thought we were home free. We passed <a href="http://www.grandtetonbrewing.com/">Grand Teton Brewing Company</a> in Victor, ID (of which I&#8217;ll posting a review of their  Sheep Eater Scotch Ale soon) and once through Tetonia we turned onto Highway 32 for West Yellowstone. It was about 7:30 PM at this point and I was anxious to get to our hotel. Unfortunately it began to snow again. After about 2 miles or so I was following an invisible car&#8217;s snow tracks in front of me and after a couple more miles the only thing visible was the enormous snow flakes that were about 5 feet in front of the truck. At this point we turned around and followed my own tracks back to Tetonia.</p>

<p>Artist&#8217;s Impression of Highway 32:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/snow.png" width="480" height="360" title="Artist's Impression of Highway 32" ></p>

<p>Back in Tetonia we called the few hotels in town and finally found one that was open and allowed pets. Rhonda asked if they had a Boeing rate and I chuckled as if anyone from Boeing had ever passed through Tetonia enough to have negotiated a corporate rate.</p>

<p>Once in the Teton Mountain View Lodge we realized it was after 9:00 PM and we were hungry. I left Rhonda, Blue, and Violet at the hotel in search of food. Tetonia, population 247, only has a few restaurants and bars and this night only one bar was open. Walking into Dave&#8217;s Pub I got quite a few looks from the locals as I approached the bar. I asked the bartender if her kitchen was still open and she said all they had was pizza. I ordered the supreme and watched as pulled a DiGiorno pizza out of the freeze and tossed it into the oven. I ordered a Bud Light in an attempt to fit in and the fellow next to me introduced himself. His name was Jim and said &#8220;my daddy always told me to make friends with the biggest man in the bar.&#8221; (I&#8217;m 6&#8217;4&#8221;.) I told him our story and turned down his many offers of tequila as I waited for my DiGiorno to finish. I felt validated in my need to turn around and give up for the night as more locals came through the down exclaiming &#8220;it&#8217;s coming down out there&#8221; in much more colorful language. Jim informed me the snow wasn&#8217;t normal for this late of April and as my pizza finished he wished me good luck on my drive back to the hotel. We ate our pizza, finished our growler of Blue Paddle, and called it a night.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/teton-mountain-view-lodge.jpg" width="480" height="321" title="Teton Mountain View Lodge" ></p>

<p>Total driving on day 4 was over 500 miles through Colorado, Wyoming, and Idaho.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/30/atlanta-to-seattle-day-3/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/30/atlanta-to-seattle-day-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 3</h1>

<p>Day 3 we left smelly Lexington heading for Fort Collins, CO. The drive through the second-half of Nebraska was much like the first-half, boring and uneventful except for a burnt-out headlight. As mentioned in a previous post, my &#8220;get up and go&#8221; personality doesn&#8217;t like not moving forward, so fixing it was not on the books.</p>

<p>The scenery changed almost immediately after passing the Nebraska-Colorado line. What was mostly drab plains and farmland became colorful rolling hills. Colorado was the first state that we saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wind_turbine">wind turbines</a> (though my memory may be blurring the states&#8230;). For whatever reason I am mesmerized by these and would point them out to Rhonda whenever I spotted them. We saw almost as many turbines as we saw <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pronghorn">pronghorn antelope</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/colorado.jpg" width="476" height="480" title="Colorado State Line" ></p>

<p>We planned for a short drive this day so we could visit <a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/">New Belgium Brewing</a> in the afternoon. Prior to the brewery though we checked in to our hotel and grabbed some lunch. We ate at <a href="http://www.wildboarcoffee.com/">Wild Boar Coffee</a> right next Colorado State University. Wild Boar&#8217;s food was awesome and their beer list was equally impressive. I had <a href="http://www.odells.com/">Odell Brewing Company&#8217;s</a> <a href="http://odellbrewing.com/beers/myrcenary">Myrcenary Double IPA</a> and Rhonda had Odell&#8217;s <a href="http://odellbrewing.com/beers/classic/90_shilling">90 Shilling Ale</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/new-belgium-brewing.jpg" width="480" height="360" title="New Belgium Brewing" ></p>

<p>After lunch we made our way to New Belgium. Not wanting to leave the dogs cooped up in the truck for the 90-minute brewery tour we decided to hang out in the tasting room. Rhonda volunteered to drive so I could partake in New Belgium&#8217;s numerous offerings. Blue Paddle was still my favorite of the day but Drew&#8217;s Ale and <a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/beer/detail.aspx?id=6f2b4470-1255-4b85-b618-ec702fcf7a05">Abbey</a> were equally tasty. My least favorite was Sara&#8217;s Red brewed with beets, licorice, fennel, and rosemary. I agreed with my server that the fennel and licorice were a bit redundant, especially since I like neither. Unlike breweries in Georgia, New Belgium is able to sell direct from the brewery including growlers. We filled up our growler with Blue Paddle, picked up a 12-pack of Sunshine and bombers of <a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/beer/detail.aspx?id=e5d60cce-6eea-4ef9-a300-0a46e8ce5123">Le Terroir</a> and <a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/beer/detail.aspx?id=629cd028-e87d-45d1-a068-a252e5db2cfd">Imperial Berliner-Weisse</a>, as well as a shirt for Rhonda and one for a friend back in Atlanta.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/new-belgium-brewing-taps.jpg" width="480" height="360" title="Taps at New Belgium Brewing" ></p>

<p>The highlights of the drive were the beautiful scenery of Colorado and of course our stop at New Belgium Brewing.</p>

<p>Total driving on day 3 was only 300 miles through Nebraska and Colorado.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/28/atlanta-to-seattle-day-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/28/atlanta-to-seattle-day-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 2</h1>

<p>After watching it rain and hail for about 30 minutes Tuesday morning it finally settled down and I examined the tarp over the truck bed. I commended myself for such a fine jimmy-rigging job and after a quick breakfast we hit the road. Thanks to Google Maps we missed our exit onto I-70 and a few U-turns later we were on the right road.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/nebraska.jpg" width="480" height="367" title="Nebraska State Line" ></p>

<p>The drive through Missouri and Nebraska was boring and uneventful. It was windy, testing the limits of our tarp. After feeling as if the truck were going to take off from the road after a big gust we pulled over and removed the tarp for the rest of the drive. It was this stop when we realized we may have under-packed for the trip, not realizing how cold it was in the rest of the country. Stopping for gas, I was confused that <em>Plus</em> was the cheapest gas, but soon realized it was because of the added <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethanol_fuel">ethanol</a> (Thanks <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Energy_Policy_Act_of_2005">government subsidized agriculture</a>!). We made decent time thanks to the 75 MPH speed limit through the state.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/gas.jpg" width="360" height="480" title="Government Subsidized Gas" ></p>

<p>Our destination for day 2 was dinner with Kenneth, a long-time friend and co-worker, in Kearney, NE. Of course I picked a beer stop for us; <a href="http://http://www.thunderheadbrewing.com/">Thunderhead Brewing Company</a>. I had first heard about Thunderhead on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Brewing_Network">The Brewing Network</a> and was surprised that little, ol&#8217; Kearney could have such a cool sounding brewpub. With over 10 beers on tap I had two samplers of their beers. Their fruit-flavored wheats were tasty but their cream ale and dry stout were my favorites. From The Brewing Network show I learned Thunderhead uses corn in several of their beers and you can certainly taste it in their cream ale. Catching up with Kenneth was fun. Rhonda had heard plenty of stories about Kenneth and she enjoyed finally meeting him. After dinner we were off to our hotel in Lexington, NE, another 30 miles down the road. Lexington was unremarkable except for the smell&#8230;</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/thunderhead-brewing.jpg" width="360" height="480" title="Thunderhead Brewing Company" ></p>

<p>The highlight of the drive was the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Platte_River_Road_Archway_Monument">Great Platte River Road Archway Monument</a>, an archway extending across I-80. According to Kenneth it&#8217;s deemed a &#8220;temporary&#8221; structure through a loophole in the Interstate Highway System program, allowing its construction.</p>

<p>Total driving on day 2 was over 600 miles through Missouri, the corner of Iowa, and Nebraska.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something New]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/24/something-new-atlanta-to-seattle/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/24/something-new-atlanta-to-seattle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlanta to Seattle - Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/24/atlanta-to-seattle-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/04/24/atlanta-to-seattle-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>My fiancé Rhonda and I have picked up and moved to Seattle so that she can pursue a job at Boeing working on their 787 Dreamliner. We opted to make the cross-country drive rather than fly. This series of posts will be a recap of our drive. Here&#8217;s our adventure&#8230;</em></p>

<h1>Day 1</h1>

<p>Our first day we left Atlanta heading for St. Louis. The drive through Georgia and most of Tennessee was a familiar one that I&#8217;ve done several times having gone to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bonnaroo_Music_Festival">Bonnaroo Music Festival</a> in Manchester, TN for the past 6 years. We stopped for lunch in Nashville at <a href="http://www.jacksbarbque.com/">Jack&#8217;s BBQ</a>. Their pork and beef brisket sandwiches are awesome. Jack&#8217;s came highly recommended and lived up to the hype. After lunch we spent the next hour in the Home Depot parking lot jimmy-rigging a tarp across the back of the truck for the impending rain we saw in the forecast. My &#8220;get up and go&#8221; personality was very frustrated by this seemingly waste of time that was eating into our driving time. Once we finally had the right combination of rope, carabiners, and bungee cords we hit the road again. The next few hours were uneventful and we arrived in St. Louis around 7:00 local time.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/kentucky.jpg" width="480" height="340" title="Kentucky State Line" ></p>

<p>Dinner in St. Louis was spent catching up with our friends Rich and Marilyn who had moved to St. Louis a few years back. We arrived to an open bottle of <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/583/34514">Schlafly Reserve barleywine</a> and the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Big_Green_Egg">Big Green Egg</a> heating up. We tied up the dogs to a tree in the backyard and relaxed with Rich and Marilyn and their two sons Ian and Evan. Evan only hung out for an hour or so before his bedtime and Ian stayed up late until about 8:30. We talked about our move, the drive, Seattle, St. Louis and of course&#8230;beer. Rich is an avid <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sweetwater_Brewing_Company">Sweetwater</a> fan so we brought him a case of <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/273/751">Sweetwater&#8217;s staple 420 Pale Ale</a>, and bombers of <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/273/19488">Happy Ending</a> and <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/273/66786">Mean Joe Bean</a>. (Sweetwater doesn&#8217;t distribute to Missouri&#8230;) The Schlafly Reserve barleywine was very tasty, not as hoppy or sweet as some, making it very drinkable. We moved on to lighter fair after that, having my first taste of <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/192/933">New Belgium&#8217;s Blue Paddle pilsner</a> and some <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/583/1629">Schlafly pale ale</a>. Blue Paddle is amazing.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/schlafly-reserve-barleywine.jpg" width="360" height="480" title="Schlafly Reserve Barleywine" ></p>

<p>In between beers we marveled at the Big Green Egg, discussed grilling and BBQ&#8217;ing, and compared and contrasted Jack&#8217;s BBQ&#8217;s 6 different BBQ sauces. Dinner was chicken wings, pork chops, and kebobs, all delicious. After dinner Ian went to bed, we watched some TV and played with Rich&#8217;s latest toy, a green laser. He learned about it on his recent safari to South Africa where their guide used it to point out stars at night. As soon as we have a permanent address, I&#8217;ll be buying one myself!</p>

<p>We left for the hotel around 10:00 staying in a <a href="http://www.ichotelsgroup.com/redirect?path=hd&amp;brandCode=SB&amp;regionCode=1&amp;localeCode=en&amp;hotelCode=STLMO">nearby Staybridge Suites</a>. It was my first stay in an extended stay property and the extra room was enjoyable for the dogs. Unfortunately that night it stormed and the dogs kept us up half the night.</p>

<p>The best sights of the drive were <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nickajack_Lake">Nickajack Lake</a> just past Chattanooga and the first spotting of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gateway_Arch">Gateway Arch</a> in St. Louis.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/gateway-arch.jpg" width="360" height="480" title="St. Louis Gateway Arch" ></p>

<p>Total driving on day 1 was just over 500 miles  through Georgia, Tennessee, Kentucky, Illinois, and Missouri.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global Website Performance with Amazon EC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/31/global-website-performance-with-amazon-ec2/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/31/global-website-performance-with-amazon-ec2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ec2-china-response-times-crop.png" width="141" height="100" title="ec2-china-response-times-crop" ></p>

<p>Recently I&#8217;ve been looking at options to improve the performance of our websites in certain regions of the world, specifically China. While there are an infinite number of ways to improve performance a pretty basic one is to reduce the physical distance between users and the website. This means if our users are in China, we need to run our website in China or as close as we can get.</p>

<p>To get a feel for how our website would perform if it was hosted in region I setup a test to compare a U.S. hosted website and an in-region hosted website, in this case in <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/">Amazon Web Services EC2&#8217;s</a> <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2010/04/29/announcing-asia-pacific-singapore-region/">Singapore location</a>. Throwing another hat in the ring, I decided to test the same U.S. website but delivered via <a href="http://www.akamai.com/">Akamai</a>. For those who don&#8217;t know, Akamai has a global <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_delivery_network">content delivery network</a> (CDN) providing accelerated network delivery for static and dynamic content.  This gives us the following test resources:</p>

<ol>
<li>A static resource  served from the East coast of the U.S.</li>
<li>A static resource served from the East coast of the U.S. but delivered by Akamai.</li>
<li>A static resource served from Amazon&#8217;s Asia Pacific region in  Singapore.</li>
</ol>


<p>The resource is the same static 30KB image in each case. Using a monitoring service, I sampled each resource every 5 minutes from Beijing, Hong Kong, and Shanghai. The test ran for a little over 3 weeks. Without further ado, here are results&#8230;</p>

<h3>Response Times</h3>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ec2-china-response-times-e1296404574953.png" width="479" height="289" title="ec2-china-response-times" ></p>

<p>Average response times over the 2 weeks  were:</p>

<ol>
<li>Origin - <em>3.49 seconds.</em></li>
<li>Akamai - <em>1.73 seconds.</em></li>
<li>EC2 - <em>0.66 seconds.</em></li>
</ol>


<p>From these numbers you can see how much of an impact distance can have and even more so how much of a positive impact Akamai can have on delivering your content. In this case the physical distance &#8220;as the crow flies&#8221; between the origin and the same content through Akamai is the same but Akamai can greatly increase performance over the &#8220;normal internet&#8221;.</p>

<h3>Availability</h3>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/ec2-china-availability-e1296404625651.png" width="478" height="288" title="ec2-china-availability" ></p>

<p>Average availability over the 2 weeks  were:</p>

<ol>
<li>Origin - <em>99.90%</em></li>
<li>Akamai - <em>99.25%</em></li>
<li>EC2 - <em>99.92%</em></li>
</ol>


<p>These numbers might seem low for serving a static image but are typical of what we&#8217;ve seen for China. Akamai&#8217;s availability is surprising as its the lowest of the lot.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>The test results certainly support the hypothesis that reducing the distance between a website and its users will result in better performance. This is a function of the &#8220;speed of light problem&#8221; and reducing the number of hops between the two points. Reducing the number of hops would also improve availability by reducing the points of failure in between.</p>

<p>To summarize, no big surprises here, moving your applications and data closer to your customers can substantially improve the performance of your applications. Amazon&#8217;s  availability regions in North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific greatly reduce the barrier to deploying your applications globally and making for a better customer experience. This, of course, assumes your applications can be deployed in multiple locations and not impact data or transaction integrity&#8230;this is easier said than done. If you absolutely can&#8217;t move host your applications globally, Akamai can certainly help deliver your website faster. I expect we would see an even better improvement combining Akamai and an in-region hosted application.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting: Sierra Nevada Hoptimum]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/24/tasting-sierra-nevada-hoptimum/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/24/tasting-sierra-nevada-hoptimum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Hoptimum</em></strong> is a &#8220;whole-cone imperial IPA&#8221; from Sierra Nevada Brewing Co. From what I can tell this is their first full-release American Double/Imperial IPA. Making it extra special, <em>Hoptimum</em> is brewed with a &#8220;New Proprietary Variety&#8221; hop. As with all of Sierra Nevada&#8217;s brews, they use whole cone hops rather than pellets.</p>

<p>Sierra Nevada has been on a bit of a tear the past couple years, churning  out many new year-round, seasonal, and one-time brews. Their 30th  anniversary seems to have reinvigorated them.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sierra-nevada-hoptimum-bottle.jpg" width="411" height="480" title="sierra-nevada-hoptimum-bottle" ></p>

<h2>Beer Facts</h2>

<p><strong>Name</strong>: Hoptimum</p>

<p><strong> Style</strong>: Imperial IPA</p>

<p><strong> Brewery</strong>: Sierra Nevada Brewing Co.</p>

<p><strong> Released</strong>: One-time</p>

<p><strong> Availability</strong>: 24 oz. bottle and draft</p>

<p><strong> From the bottle</strong>:</p>

<blockquote>A  group of hop-heads and publicans challenged our Beer Camp brewers to  push the extremes of whole-cone hop brewing. The result is this: a 100  IBU, whole-cone hurricane of flavor. Simply put —Hoptimum: the biggest  whole-cone IPA we have ever produced. Aggressively hopped, dry-hopped,  AND torpedoed with our exclusive new hop varieties for ultra-intense  flavors and aromas.

Resinous &#8220;new-school&#8221; and exclusive hop  varieties carry the bold and aromatic nose. The flavor follows the aroma  with layers of aggressive hoppiness, featuring notes of grapefruit  rind, rose, lilac, cedar, and tropical fruit—all culminating in a dry  and lasting finish.</blockquote>


<p><strong>Hops</strong>: German Magnum, Simcoe, &#8220;New Proprietary Variety&#8221;, Citra and Chinook</p>

<p><strong>Malts</strong>: Two-row pale, Golden Promise, Munich, and Wheat</p>

<p><strong>Yeast</strong>: &#8220;Ale&#8221;</p>

<p><strong>OG</strong>: 22.8 Plato</p>

<p><strong>FG</strong>: 4.5 Plato</p>

<p><strong>IBUs</strong>: 100</p>

<p><strong>ABV</strong>: 10.4%</p>

<h2>Tasting</h2>

<p><strong>Serving</strong>: From a 24 oz. bottle into a Dogfish Head Signature Glass.</p>

<p><strong>Appearance</strong>: Clear, burnt orange in color. Couple fingers of head but dissipates quickly leaving nice lacing.</p>

<p><strong>Aroma</strong>: Strong hop aroma, but not as &#8220;smelly&#8221; as expected. Resin, pine, and pineapple notes with sweet malt present.</p>

<p><strong>Mouthfeel</strong>: Medium carbonation, perfect for this beer. Syrupy mouthfeel, but not cloying and disappears after each sip.</p>

<p><strong>Taste</strong>: Very hoppy and bitter but balanced by the sweet malt. Slight alcohol after hops and sweetness fade. Citrus and pine from the hops.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sierra-nevada-hoptimum-glass.jpg" width="472" height="480" title="sierra-nevada-hoptimum-glass" ></p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p><em>Hoptimum</em> is my favorite kind of IPA/Imperial IPA. It has plenty of hop bitterness but flavor to match as well. What makes it great in my book is that it doesn&#8217;t linger or ruin my palate. It&#8217;s flavor and mouthfeel disappear after each sip, leaving you wanting another. <em>Hoptimum</em> is supposed to be a one-time offering from Sierra Nevada, but as those go they sometimes turn into year-round or seasonal releases. This is one that I hope goes that route, it&#8217;s too good to not brew again,</p>

<p><strong>Food pairings</strong>: A full-flavored soup or stew.</p>

<p><strong>Cellar-able</strong>: No.</p>

<p><strong>Comparable beers</strong>: Port Brewing Hop 15, Russian River Pliny the Elder, Southern Tier 2XIPA.</p>

<h2>Links</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.sierranevada.com/beers/hoptimum.html">Brewery Link</a></li>
<li><a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/140/55939">BeerAdvocate</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.ratebeer.com/beer/sierra-nevada-hoptimum/117825/">ratebeer</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Chrome OS Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/24/google-chrome-os-review/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/24/google-chrome-os-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever since <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2009/07/introducing-google-chrome-os.html">Google Chrome OS</a> was announced in July of 2009 I&#8217;ve been looking forward to seeing what hits the streets. Fortunately, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Chrome_OS#Cr-48_prototype_hardware">Cr-48 Chrome OS laptop</a> landed on my desk today and I&#8217;ve spent the evening trying it out.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/cr-48-box.jpg" width="480" height="360" title="cr-48-box" ></p>

<p>Given that the laptop is &#8220;prototype&#8221; hardware I&#8217;ll keep my review to the OS itself. For brevity&#8217;s sake, I&#8217;ll keep this to a stream of consciousness type review:</p>

<ul>
    <li>Initial startup only took a few seconds then after setup of the wireless it took a few minutes to download the OS updates. <em>So far so good.</em></li>
    <li>Once signed in, I&#8217;m taken to a Chrome browser window and a well-designed Get Started page. <em>Meh.</em></li>
    <li>I immediately go to <em>Settings</em> and find not much there. <em>Meh.</em></li>
    <li>Loading my most common tabs everything seems pretty snappy. <em>Good.</em></li>
    <li>I open up my WordPress Admin and start this review, take a photo of the Cr-48 box and wonder how I&#8217;m going to load the photos from my camera. Plugging in the camera (a five-year old Sony DSC-W50) I&#8217;m able to load the photos straight from the mounted disk, though there&#8217;s no easy way to browse and look at multiple photos. <em>Surprised it worked at all.</em></li>
    <li><a href="http://www.picnik.com/">picnik</a> works perfectly on Chrome OS to resize the photo. <em>Cool.</em></li>
    <li>I can&#8217;t figure out how to unmount the camera, so I just unplug it. <em>Boo.</em></li>
    <li>Having opened up about 15 tabs I start to wish I could pull a few out into different windows and alt-tab between them. Never has a favicon been more important. <em>Boo.</em></li>
    <li>All the while, everything is pretty snappy. There&#8217;s a noticeable, but tolerable slowdown when loading multiple pages in the background. <em>Meh.</em></li>
    <li>Page rendering is quick but other page operations such as finding text on a page is slower than normal. Tab switching starts to slow as well. <em>Meh.</em></li>
    <li>After having many tabs open for a while, I can notice Chrome OS start to preserve resources and &#8220;hide&#8221; background pages. The tabs are still there but switching to them triggers the browser to repaint the page. <em>Meh.</em></li>
    <li>Pasting within my blog post cause the page to scroll vertically at times, but not every time. <em>Annoying.</em></li>
    <li>Opening Pandora, Flash is noticeably slower, but is functional. <em>Good (if only for Pandora).</em></li>
    <li>Google Docs is frustrating to use. There&#8217;s a noticeable delay in edits and moving around in spreadsheets and documents. <em>Boo.</em></li>
    <li>There&#8217;s no way to take screenshots within Chrome OS. <em>Boo.</em></li>
    <li>Waking the laptop from sleep is ridiculously fast. <em>Awesome.</em></li>
</ul>


<p>As a software architect that still dabbles in code, Chrome OS certainly can&#8217;t cut it for me. I need a terminal, the ability to install additional &#8220;real&#8221; applications, Java, an IDE, etc. but I expect Chrome OS would suffice for 90% of the population.</p>

<p>From a hardware perspective Cr-48 hardware is definitely a &#8220;prototype&#8221; and detracts from the overall experience. For casual browsing it suffices, but I can&#8217;t see myself using the Cr-48 for long periods of time.</p>

<p>All in all, I&#8217;m impressed and I tend to fling more insults at Google than complements. Given the success of the iPad and the &#8220;limited&#8221; features of Chrome OS, it seems a tablet is a more likely form factor for Chrome OS than a laptop. Microsoft and to a lesser extent Apple should be worried.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PHP on AWS Elastic Beanstalk]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/20/php-on-aws-elastic-beanstalk/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.cameronstokes.com/2011/01/20/php-on-aws-elastic-beanstalk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The latest service offering from Amazon Web Services is <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/">AWS Elastic Beanstalk</a>, allowing companies to deploy applications to Amazon&#8217;s cloud and let Amazon handle deployment and scaling of infrastructure automatically.</p>

<p>From Amazon:</p>

<blockquote>You simply upload your application, and Elastic Beanstalk automatically handles the deployment details of capacity provisioning, load balancing, auto-scaling, and application health monitoring.</blockquote>


<p>While Amazon claims they&#8217;re working on other platforms, initially Beanstalk only supports Java applications deployed in the <a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/">Apache Tomcat 6</a> container. However&#8230;using <a href="http://quercus.caucho.com/">Quercus</a>, a &#8220;100% Java implementation of PHP 5&#8221; from <a href="http://caucho.com/">Caucho</a>, we can run PHP using AWS Elastic Beanstalk. All it takes is setting up a simple <a href="http://maven.apache.org/">Maven</a> project.</p>

<p>The first step is to setup the Caucho Maven repository and our dependencies in our POM:</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='xml'><span class='line'> <span class="nt">&lt;dependencies&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;dependency&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;groupId&gt;</span>com.caucho<span class="nt">&lt;/groupId&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;artifactId&gt;</span>resin<span class="nt">&lt;/artifactId&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;version&gt;</span>4.0.14<span class="nt">&lt;/version&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;/dependency&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;/dependencies&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;repositories&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;repository&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;id&gt;</span>caucho<span class="nt">&lt;/id&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;url&gt;</span>http://caucho.com/m2/<span class="nt">&lt;/url&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;releases&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nt">&lt;enabled&gt;</span>true<span class="nt">&lt;/enabled&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;/releases&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;snapshots&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>          <span class="nt">&lt;enabled&gt;</span>false<span class="nt">&lt;/enabled&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>      <span class="nt">&lt;/snapshots&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nt">&lt;/repository&gt;</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="nt">&lt;/repositories&gt;</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>For this demo, I used the <em>web.xml</em> and PHP files from Caucho&#8217;s Quercus download and added a <em>phpinfo.php</em> page to show <em>phpinfo()</em> output. Here&#8217;s what our Maven <em>webapp</em> directory structure looks like:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/maven-webapp.png" width="613" height="280" title="maven-webapp" ></p>

<p>Running <em>mvn package</em> produces a war file that can be deployed to AWS Elastic Beanstalk without any further modifications. After waiting a few minutes for the EC2 instance to start up, here&#8217;s our <em>phpinfo.php</em> file running on AWS:</p>

<p><img src="http://www.cameronstokes.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/aws-beanstalk-phpinfo.png" width="765" height="800" title="aws-beanstalk-phpinfo" ></p>

<p>That&#8217;s it&#8230;we have PHP running on AWS Elastic Beanstalk. It could not have been easier. Chances are Amazon will add PHP support down the road but until then you can run your own PHP applications using Quercus.</p>

<p>The full project code can be downloaded on GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/clstokes/aws-elastic-beanstalk-php">https://github.com/clstokes/aws-elastic-beanstalk-php</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
